# JENNIE ROGNESS

3359 Dudley St., Dearborn, Mich. 48124 815-666-3768 | jrogness262@gmail.com

# About me

I'm a designer who can brainstorm, research, write, edit as well as execute attractive designs. Organizing information into a visual is my specialty. Whether it's a graphic, brochure, magazine spread or social media image, I like the challenge of creating an easy-to-understand design.

# **Portfolio**

COROFLOT.COM/JROGNESS

# Skills

#### **PLATFORMS**

Macintosh and PC

#### **SOFTWARE**

Expert knowledge:

Adobe Creative Suite

- Photoshop
- InDesign
- Illustrator

Quark XPress

Macromedia Freehand

Microsoft Word

CCI publishing software

Saxotech publishing software

#### Working knowledge:

нтмі

CSS

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Powerpoint

Adobe Bridge

#### **KNOWLEDGE**

AP Style

Compliance

Editing

Image Editing

**Printing Processes** 

# Professional experience

#### SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER

**APRIL 2014 TO JANUARY 2017** 

Catholic Order of Foresters, Naperville, Ill.

**Responsibilities:** Design quarterly magazine Catholic Forester; Create corporate advertising and marketing collateral, including direct mail letters, fliers, postcards, wall and standalone banners, email blasts, forms, logos, etc.; Photo editing

# SPECIAL SECTIONS DESIGNER

FEBRUARY 2013 TO APRIL 2014

Gatehouse Media, Oakbrook Terrace, Ill.

Responsibilities: Design tabloid, broadsheet and magazine sections for members of Gatehouse Media; Design content pages for More Content Now news service; Convert and upload InDesign and Quark documents to More Content Now news service website; Export final pages to news sites; Create graphics and/or illustrations for More Content Now news service; Create ads and prototype websites for the Gatehouse online division

#### ASSISTANT DESIGN EDITOR

MAY 2010 TO OCTOBER 2012

The Journal Gazette, Fort Wayne, Ind.

Responsibilities: Delegate projects and daily work to design staff; Maintain publication style; Help train staff on current or new technology; Design section fronts, special sections and inside pages; Photo editing: including photo selection from local and wire news services, color correction, illustration; Research and create information graphics; Create marketing materials such as advertisements or static web banners to promote various special sections, unique content and the publication

#### **GRAPHIC ARTIST/DESIGNER**

SEPTEMBER 2001 TO MAY 2010

The Journal Gazette, Fort Wayne, Ind.

**Responsibilities:** Design section fronts, special sections and inside pages; Photo editing: including photo selection from local and wire news services, color correction, illustration; Research and create information graphics

# **Achievements**

FIRST PLACE, USE OF GRAPHICS

INDIANA ASSOCIATED PRESS MANAGING EDITORS

Parkview Field graphic, 2010

# SECOND PLACE, BEST INFORMATIONAL GRAPHICS

#### SOCIETY OF PROFESSIONAL JOURNALISTS, INDIANA CHAPTER

Pressing Forward graphic, 2008

# **Education**

# **BALL STATE UNIVERSITY**

**FALL 1997 TO SUMMER 2001** 

Muncie, Ind.

Bachelor of Science degree in Journalism Graphics; Geography minor

#### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

PRESENT

Online

HTML, CSS & Web Design Circuit